retireonline.com 2006-03-17

# JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services

Trust is the foundation of any important relationship. When you entrust your assets to our care, you entrust us with your financial goals. We take that responsibility seriously at JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services. We honor your trust by striving to provide excellent service and protect your privacy with integrity.

Privacy is an integral part of our online services. This Privacy and Security Policy describes the kinds of personal information we collect, how we use it and, perhaps most importantly, how we protect it.

**Privacy and Security Policy Sections:**

  * What Kinds of Information Do We Collect?
  * How Do We Use the Information We Collect? 
  * How Do We Protect Your Information?
  * Our Use of Cookies 
  * Secure Online Account Access
  * Web Browser Requirements 
  * Adobe Acrobat Reader 
  * Macromedia Flash 

| 

   What Kinds of Information Do We Collect? 

|   
  
---|---  
  
The information we collect about you generally falls into one of the following categories:  
---  
  
| Information such as address, Social Security number, income and demographic data that we receive from payroll reports that your employer provides.   
  
| Transactional information about your accounts such as investment choices, account balances and transaction history.   
  
Additionally, we occasionally survey participants to determine their satisfaction with the services we offer.

Also, if you conduct business online with JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services, you may notice our use of Internet "cookies" — identifiers we transfer to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser. These cookies enable our systems to recognize your browser and customize your experience on our Web site. See our discussion below of cookies and how we use them.

   How Do We Use the Information We Collect?

|   
  
---|---  
  
We use the information we collect primarily to maintain your accounts and process your transactions. In doing so, we may share this information with affiliated financial service providers such as the transfer agent, distributor and investment adviser for our mutual funds. We also may share this information with unaffiliated companies we hire to perform administrative services. Examples include print and mail service providers that help distribute investor materials such as annual reports.

Additionally, we may share this information with other entities under certain limited circumstances permitted by law such as to resolve a dispute or prevent fraud.

We rely on the information we collect to help us better understand you and your investing needs. Occasionally, we may share this information with our financial services affiliates and with unaffiliated companies we hire to help us with our research efforts.

   How Do We Protect Your Information?

|   
  
---|---  
  
We treat all personal information we collect as confidential information. Under no circumstances do we sell any of the personal information we collect. The unaffiliated companies with which we share personal information are prohibited by contract from using this information for any purpose other than to provide service to us.

To further safeguard your information within JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services, our policies only allow access to individuals who must have it to service your account. We maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect this information. We treat information about our former clients with the same care we take with our current clients’ information.

   Cookies and JavaScript

|   
  
---|---  
  
If you conduct business with JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services online, you may notice our use of Internet cookies. Cookies enable our systems to recognize your browser and customize your experience on our Web site and help us better understand how our investors use our Web site.

A cookie is a small piece of information placed on your computer by the Web site you are visiting. It allows the Web site to remember or recognize your computer during subsequent visits. Different Web sites use cookies for different purposes. 

There are two types of cookies on the internet

Temporary Cookies - Cookies that are stored on your computer only during your browsing session, and are automatically deleted from your computer when you close your browser.

Persistent Cookies - Cookies that are stored on your computer and are not deleted when you close your browser.

**JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services cookie requirements**

We use only temporary cookies. We store temporary cookies on each secure page. These cookies store a session ID that allows you to move from page to page and not have to log in each time. Once you properly log out and shutdown your browser, the temporary cookie on your computer must be deleted.

  * Cookies must be enabled on your browser to access our site.
  * We do not collect any information from your computer and it does not leave any retrievable information on your hard drive

**JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services also uses pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising.**

These GIF files are provided by our ad management partner, DoubleClick. These files enable DoubleClick to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. The cookie was placed by us, or by another advertiser who works with DoubleClick. With both cookies and Spotlight technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. For more information about DoubleClick, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to [DoubleClick.](http://www.doubleclick.net/us/corporate/privacy)

**JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services JavaScript requirements**

JavaScript is an object oriented scripting language for Internet Applications. Most sites today use JavaScript to perform certain actions on their Web sites. We use JavaScript on the site to run certain features

  * JavaScript must be enabled on your browsers to get all features offered on our site.
  * Visit the [Netscape Navigator](http://www.netscape.com/) or [Microsoft Internet Explorer](http://www.microsoft.com/) Web sites to learn how to enable JavaScript on your browser.

   Secure Online Account Access

|   
  
---|---  
  
Web Security and You

Protecting your privacy and security is a shared responsibility. We affirm our commitment to safeguard your personal information; however, it is imperative that you protect your Personal Access Code to prevent unauthorized access to your accounts. For this reason, we strongly suggest that you do not share your Personal Access Code with anyone. If you do choose to give it to someone, such as a so-called "financial aggregator" that combines information about you from multiple sources over the Internet, you do so at your own risk. We cannot be responsible for any losses you may incur as a result. Registration is the unique User ID and Personal Access Code combination used to log in to a secure and customized My Accounts Homepage containing your JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services accounts and other services. Any personal or financial information you provide during the Registration process is kept confidential, as stated in this Privacy and Security Policy.

To help protect your personal information, JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services employs the following security mechanisms when setting up a Registration account.

You will receive or have received a secured Personal Access Code . Any time you visit the site, you have the option of changing that Personal Access Code. The new code you establish must meet the following requirements: 

| The Personal Access Code must be six (6) to ten (10) characters in length.   
---|---  
  
| The Personal Access Code may be a combination of letters and numbers, or be entirely numeric.   
  
| The Personal Access Code may not include special characters (example: &,%,\, etc.).  
  
| The Personal Access Code cannot begin with a zero.   
  
| The Personal Access Code cannot contain a string of four or more numbers or letters that match your Social Security number and/or User ID.   
  
| The Personal Access Code must not have more than two consecutive repeating letters or numbers. (acceptable: 113355 or AABBCC, not acceptable: 111333 or AAABBB)   
  
| The Personal Access Code must have no more than two increments. (acceptable: 124578 or ABDEGH, not acceptable: 123567 or ABCEFG)   
  
| The Personal Access Code must have no more than two decrements. (acceptable: 875421 or HGEDBA, not acceptable: 765321 or GFECBA)  
  
| The Personal Access Code should not be your date of birth.   
  
| The Personal Access Code should not be composed so that it can be easily guessed. (example: your name, phone number, etc.)   
  
A timeout feature will automatically end your secure session if you are not active for 30 minutes. To restart your Registration session, you will need to log in again. After three failed attempts to log in, we lock the account to prevent access to personal information within the Web site.

If you forgot your Personal Access Code or locked your account, you can reset yourself using the Security Access information or JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services can help to re-establish your internet session. Contact Us if you need help in gaining access

   Web Browser Requirements

|   
  
---|---  
  
We require users to access their accounts online with Netscape (version 6.0 or later), Microsoft Internet Explorer (version 5.0 or later). These browsers use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology with RSA Public Key encryption. This technology helps enable the security of your online sessions. If for any reason your session is no longer secure, you will be disconnected from online account access.

If a session is secure, it means that it is encrypted. Every secure page on JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services Web site has been secured with a digital certificate by RSA Data Security, Inc. We use SSL, RSA Public Key encryption and proprietary encryption algorithms to secure your connection when you are accessing your account online. JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services supports 128-bit encryption to provide you with secure access to your account information.

However, your browser may only support 40-bit encryption. If your browser does not support 128-bit encryption, we recommend that you upgrade your browser to a newer version. Please access the [Netscape Navigator](http://www.netscape.com/) or [Microsoft Internet Explorer ](http://www.microsoft.com/)Web sites to upgrade your browser to the current version with 128-bit encryption.

Before making an upgrade to your company’s proprietary PC, be sure to check with your computer help desk to learn about software upgrade policies.

**Browser**

| 

**Secure  
Connection **

| 

**Non-Secure Connection**  
  
---|---|---  
Netscape 6.0 or higher | 

|   
  
Microsoft Internet Explorer 5.0 or higher  | 

| 

No lock   

To view the encryption certificate, click on the image of the closed lock or the solid key on the bottom bar of your browser window. A small frame displaying site security information will appear. If you use Internet Explorer, click on the word "Subject" to verify the Web site. If you use Netscape, click on the "View Certificate" button to see information on the subject and issuer. This site may contain links to other sites. JPMorgan Retirement Plan Services is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such Web sites.   
  
We require users to have Adobe Acrobat Reader installed on their system for access to various PDF documents that we make available to our participants. Adobe® Reader® is a free software product used for viewing and printing Adobe Portable Document Format (PDF) files. Adobe Reader has become a standard product for rendering documents on the Web. 

We require users to have Macromedia Flash player installed on their systems for access to various dynamic areas on the site that we make available to our participants. Macromedia Flash player is a free software product used for viewing flash modules.
